A common trend on YouTube
is telling people
that they can make 2025 the year of
their life.
And I say those creators need to shut the
fuck up.
Because if I'm real with you for a second,
2025 isn't going to be the year of your
life. And if you nail 2025,
it's probably going to be one of those
years you see
your friends the least. Relax,
go on holiday the least.
Even if you do go on holiday,
you're going to be preoccupied with work
thoughts.
You're going to be distracted most of the
time.
Your partner's going to probably think
you're not interested in them because
you're
so focused and caught up with content
creation, what to put in tomorrow's email
marketing email. And if anything,
this could actually be one of the most
miserable
years of your life.
And that's great because it means you're
finally actually doing
the work.
People online often like to overinflate
what can be done in months, but
at the same time play down what can be
done in years.
So I thought I'd remind you a few things
from my journey to bring a little bit of a
[clicks tongue] taste of reality into it.
When I started email marketing,
I wrote emails for 10 months before
someone
actually bought what I wanted. I created,
I know it's embarrassing to say, a PDF,
and I called it "The Final Fat Loss Plan."
And even as early as 2014, I
put every single element of education
about energy balance and
calorie equations
and macronutrient constituents.
And I thought if someone paid me £19.99,
they could buy this
PDF,
and they could lose weight on their own
forever, and no one bought it. No one.
Well, one person called Mahendra.
Mahendra Patel, thank you very much, sir,
but he was also one of my face-to-face
clients,
and I actually think he just felt bad.
He bought it because he felt bad.
To prove to you how little people wanted
this, I tried giving it away in
return for people's email addresses.
And imagine this.
I A/B split tested this, said, "Hey, guys,
if you want the final fat loss plan
delivered to you by email,
give me your email address." I then in
another place
just said, "Hey,
give me your email address." I got more
email addresses just
asking than I did for the final fat loss
plan, yet that was something I was pushing
over email marketing for months.
Sometimes it can take quite literally a
year to
realize the product you created to save
people and help them and give it to them
and empower people,
and nobody fucking wants.
Before that,
I posted on social media for three
and a half years before
taking on a social media client. Now,
just before you get depressed, go home,
cry,
and bash out a little wank,
you have it so much easier than I ever
had.
And this isn't like the baby boomers.
"Oh, interest rates in our days were 18%.
You've got it so..." You have something
called the TikTokification of social
media,
whereby content is now served to you based
on your interests, not who you follow.
Back in my day,
you had to follow someone to see their
content.
So the only way we could get growth was
if someone shared it, you got a shout-out,
LadBible did a piece on you, whatever.
If you now make a perfectly created bit of
content about financial advice,
mortgage broking,
how to train your hamstrings, whatever,
the algorithms at play
will categorize your content
and serve it to people that
are interested in that
shit.
And it will give it to loads of people as
long as the piece of content is
good enough.
The reason I don't like it
when people say 2025 is your year
is the types of people that
are lured into that baity shit are
often a couple years away from hitting the
good shit.
You should all follow another YouTube
channel called Creator Booth.
The guy's called Ed Lawrence.
I studied under him.
He's a dear friend of mine.
I'm not plagiarizing his work now.
I'm plagiarizing it a little bit.
His ideas are so good
that I can't get them out of my head.
And he created this system,
which I'm going to semi rip off now,
but it's
okay because I paid Ed loads of money
when I used him as a mentor.
Level one is pretty much where the
majority of you as creators could be a
year
away from making good content.
And I know that sounds pretty depressing,
but
honestly,
it takes a long time to get good at
content, to talk to camera, to rift,
to be comfortable,
to look down the dark abyss of a lens
and pretend
there's someone there
that you're talking to on the internet.
It can take months of scripting B-roll,
upgrading camera equipment, getting
lighting, whatever it is,
to become proficient in content creation.
Some people get it done in three months.
Some people get it done in a year.
If you were to compare it to another skill
like Olympic lifting, some people pick
up the snatch in a short period of time.
Other people, it takes years.
That level of mastery, whatever. Again,
some people are doing it alongside
full-time work and something
that has nothing to do with it.
Some people are doing hours as a personal
trainer.
They're making online content, whatever.
But the more time you spend into content
creation, the quicker you can get out of
level one. Another level one task
is where you're spending time with your
clients,
understanding them as a demographic.
As a personal trainer,
you're learning who can squat, who can't,
who can bench, who
can't, what people struggle with
when it comes to weight loss, whatever.
As a level one content creator,
you're trying to grow your email list to
the first
1,000 subscribers.
You have no idea what to write emails
about, and that muscle in
your brain that gets creative over, "Oh,
that'd make an email.
Oh,
that'd make a good social media post,"
is so atrophied through not being used,
it is very, very difficult. Now,
level one creators
are sold into these videos.
2025. It's your year. You can do well.
You're not there yet.
It takes for probably majority of people
two years to escape level one and to go to
level two. At level two,
every video you put out
is getting a few thousand views.
Every email that you send
is getting a few hundred reads,
and it's getting a few
dozen people go through to your landing
page.
At level two,
you understand your demographics,
your cohorts.
The second something bad happens in your
day, you go, "I can't wait to write an
email about that."
And the second your client asks you a
question, you go, "That,
my friend,
is going to be a piece of content." Once
you've spent a bit of time at
level two,
you then start creating automations with
your email marketing.
You start connecting chatbots to your
social media posts.
You start working less with your clients.
You're probably hiring other coaches,
or you start delegating work.
You might be fortunate enough to get
yourself a Declan,
so all you need to do is
sit in front of a camera
and waffle every day.
And when you wake up the next morning,
it's a perfectly created YouTube video
where
the colors have been changed to make you
look more tanned.
However,
it makes a can of Nutonic no longer look
yellow. But we'll take that.
We'll take the loss because it makes my
skin look better.
Who cares about the product
if you're making me look good?
And then eventually,
you become a level three creator at the
top.
When you're at level three,
your business is making enough money
that you quite
literally need to spend tens of thousands
of pounds or dollars each year just to
offset your tax bill,
AKA business class flights on
that work trip
where your partner's the videographer.
At level three, as again, this
is Ed's concept, not mine,
and I will put a link to
his channel in the description. You
are looking at the Hormozis, the Iman
Gadzis, the very people saying, "2025
is going to be your
year, man." It's all right for them.
You're making 100 mil a fucking year.
But I think you could be so much happier
knowing that you probably won't.
But before you get depressed, go away
and have a wank into a tissue or a sock.
Remember this.
I'm a brown belt in Brazilian jujitsu.
I'd say a competitive one.
I'm 35, but I compete adult. Yeah,
no gyms, no bro.
Strong white belts. Oh,
strong white belts.
A white belt with good intentions
is more dangerous than a black belt with
bad
intentions. I was awful.
Then at blue belt,
I got a little bit confident.
Still rubbish.
We're talking six years into jujitsu.
It was only seven to eight years
that I realized, oh, I'm now
considerably less shit. But still,
I know in two years' time I'll be
embarrassed of the level of grappling
that I put out now.
Why am I telling you this?
Each one of those years wasn't the best
year,
but I still loved it.
I loved being a white belt just as much as
blue belt, and I
loved being a purple belt just as much as
a blue belt, and I loved being a brown
belt just as much as all the belts before.
So rather than focusing on this year being
the best year ever, because
statistically the majority of you,
especially at level one,
will not have the best
year of your life.
The years coming after it will be way
better.
Appreciate that you can still very much
enjoy every single process of it.
When you get your email list to 10
subscribers Celebrate that shit.
Every time you get a little handful of 10
or 11 more followers,
celebrate that shit. The time
that the first 10 people visit your
landing page,
even if they don't buy, celebrate
that shit.
And the time that for the first time you
get a whole automated sequence of someone
watching your social media content,
finding their whole way to become a
client,
celebrate that. The four hormones
that govern how we feel on a daily basis,
dopamine, oxytocin, serotonin, endorphins.
They're all the same the whole way up.
They are.
Sounds crazy,
but making 100 grand a month will feel the
same as making 10 grand a
month.
And 10 grand a month will feel the same as
making 4 grand a month.
And people that haven't made it yet find
that really difficult to believe.
You don't get that unhappiness
or enjoyment or fulfillment
or dopamine the whole
way up.
So 2025 is not going to be your fucking
year.
And if it's going to be a good year for
you and your business, it's going to be a
relatively miserable year for every other
part of it.
You'll probably spend some days on your
laptop for 12 hours and even get a little
twitch in your eye, which I had for years.
But that doesn't mean you can't enjoy the
shit out of every single process of that.
Because as you go from a level one to a
level two to a level three, your life
becomes easier, becomes less stressful.
And this is the only way I can say it.
The creative side of your brain
is creating content, writing emails,
structuring
different campaigns
and strategies just becomes better trained
over time.
And before you know it, it's automated.
2025 is probably going to be the year of
the struggle.
It's going to be your white belt two
years.
But the best bit is
that you can look back on 2025,
like I do when I was a white
belt, and go, "Fucking hell, I
was so dog shit there,
but I'm so proud that I
never gave up." So I'm not going to wish
you have a good year.
I'm going to say get the fuck on with it.
And if you're still not sure what you're
doing, like a good professor would give
white belts techniques
that they can use to submit people,
I'll leave you a link
for 30 ways in 30 days
that I can benefit your business.
Each one a black belt technique
that you can implement on the day
that it comes
into your inbox. And
if you don't like it at any point,
you can unsubscribe.
Now,
if you made it the whole way through
without getting depressed, I'm going to
wank into a sock.
YouTube recommends this video here,
so check that out.
I'm sure you'll love it. And if you don't,
it's not my problem. Have a good year.